<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string-array name="beerFacts">
        <item>Anchor Liberty Ale was the first modern American IPA.</item>
        <item>The first beer can was produced in 1933.</item>
        <item>Schlitz invented the tall boy can.</item>
        <item>Homebrewing in Mississippi and Alabama was only legalized in 2013.</item>
        <item>The world\rs best-selling beer is Snow, from China.</item>
        <item>-In 1814, a huge vat carrying the equivalent of 3500 barrels of beer ruptured causing a 15ft high tidal wave of beer killed eight people in London.</item>
        <item>Some people were prescribed "medical beer" during prohibition.</item>
        <item>The largest craft brewery in America is Yuengling.</item>
        <item>A beer tax was created by Abraham Lincoln to help pay for the Civil War.</item>
        <item>-To help pay for the Civil War, Congress imposed an excise tax on beer. The Revenue Act of 1862, signed into law by President Lincoln, included a tax on "all beer, lager beer, ale, porter, and other similar fermented liquors, by whatever name such liquors may be called." It may not be popular but taxing beer wasn\rt a bad idea from an economic standpoint: today, more than $48.5 billion in tax revenue is generated by the production and sale of beer and other malt beverages in the United States.</item>
        <item>Cenosillicaphobia is the fear of an empty glass of beer.</item>
        <item>-The world\rs longest hangover lasted 4 weeks after a Scotsman consumed 60 pints of beer.</item>
        <item>BrewMeister\rs, Snake Venom, is the strongest beer in the world at 67.5% alcohol content.</item>
        <item>Slugs and snails like beer.</item>
        <item>-Amsterdam pays alcoholics in beer to clean streets: 5 cans of beer for a day\rs work, plus €10 and tobacco.</item>
        <item>Until 2013, Beer was not considered an alcoholic beverage in Russia.</item>
        <item>-Until the 1970s in Belgium, beer was served in school cafeterias.</item>
        <item>-At the Wife Carrying World Championships in Finland, first prize is the wife\rs weight in beer.</item>
        <item>-The Wat Pa Maha Chedi Kaew temple in Thailand was constructed with 1 million bottles of Heineken and a local beer.</item>
        <item>-More Guinness beer is drunk in Nigeria than Ireland.</item>
        <item>-In the Land of the Pharaohs of Egypt, beer was the national currency.</item>
        <item>-In Argentina, political parties have their own brands of beer.</item>
        <item>-Norway\rs first aircraft hijacking was resolved after the hijacker surrendered his weapon in exchange for more beer.</item>
        <item>-When scientist Niels Bohr won the Nobel Prize in 1922, the Carlsberg brewery gave him a perpetual supply of beer piped into his house.</item>
        <item>-In 1963, Albert Heineken created a beer bottle that could also be used as a brick to build sustainable housing in impoverished countries.</item>
        <item>-As a rule of thumb, darker and bitter beers have higher alcohol content.</item>
        <item>-In the 13th century, some people in Norway would baptize their children with beer.</item>
        <item>-You can swim in pools of beer in Austria.</item>
        <item>-162,719 pints of Guinness beer are wasted each year due to mustaches.</item>
        <item>-President Jimmy Carter signed a bill that created an exemption from taxation of beer brewed at home for personal or family use, opening the door for today\rs craft beer brewers.</item>
        <item>-In France, Germany, Austria, Spain and the Netherlands they serve beer in McDonald\rs.</item>
        <item>-Fucking Hell is a beer named after the village of Fucking in Austria.</item>
        <item>-There\rs a brewery in Germany that\rs almost 1,000 years old. It has been in continuous operation since the year 1040.</item>
        <item>-Beer was illegal in Iceland until March 1, 1989. Now, the date is celebrated every year in Reykjavik as Bjordagur, or Beer Day.</item>
        <item>-Beer cans in Japan have braille on them so blind people don\rt confuse alcoholic drinks with soft drinks.</item>
        <item>-Joan Evans is the only person on Earth capable of balancing 237 pints of beer atop his head.</item>
        <item>-In 1956, the U.S. exploded atomic bombs near a few beers to see if they are safe to drink. They are indeed.</item>
        <item>-Carlsberg Special Brew beer was created for Winston Churchill in 1950 on the behest of the Danish government.</item>
        <item>-Table beer (1.5% alcohol) was served in Belgian schools until the 1980s.</item>
        <item>-A traditional beer tap will not work on an airplane as it will only dispense a huge amount of foam.</item>
        <item>-Steven Petrosino of New Cumberland, Pennsylvania downed 1 liter of beer or 33 ounces in a chilly 1.3 seconds in 1977 which made him a World Beer Chugging Champion according to the Guinness Book of World Records.</item>
        <item>-Beer is one of the world\rs oldest prepared beverages, possibly dating back to the early Neolithic or 9500 BC.</item>
        <item>-In 1814, almost 400,000 gallons of beer flooded several streets in London after a huge vat ruptured in the parish of St. Giles.</item>
        <item>-Stanford researchers found that beer bubbles create a gravity-defying loop. Bubbles head up in the center where frictional drag from the glass is less and down on the outside as the top gets crowded.</item>
        <item>-The Ancient Egyptians built the pyramids under the influence. According to Patrick McGovern, an archaeologist from the University of Pennsylvania, workers at Giza received about four liters of beer a day.</item>
        <item>-Beer prevents kidney stones. A study published in American Journal of Epidemiology estimated that a bottle of beer consumed every day reduces the risk by 40%.</item>
        <item>-Beer commercials in the US aren\rt really allowed to show people actually drinking the beer. It\rs a US law that people cannot actually be shown consuming an alcoholic beverage on television.</item>
        <item>-The study of beer and beer-making even has an official scientific name - zythology. It derives from the Greek words “zythos” (beer) and “logos” (study).</item>
        <item>-The most beer-drinking country in the world is the Czech Republic. With an incredible per capita beer consumption of almost 40 gallons a year, the Czechs are way out in front in the beer drinking world league table.</item>
        <item>-The world´s most expensive beer is Belgian\rs "Vielle Bon Secours". One bottle costs around 1000 American dollars.</item>
        <item>-Experimenting with beer has taken many forms. John Lubbock, an 18th-century English biologist, studied the behavior of beer on drunken ants.</item>
        <item>-Old Vikings believed that in their heaven called Valhalla, there is a giant goat whose udders provided unlimited supply of beer.</item>
        <item>-Nowadays, there are about 400 types of beer in the world. Belgium is the country that has the most individual beer brands.</item>
        <item>-Ancient Babylonians were so serious about brewing beer that if anyone brewed a bad batch, they would drown him in it as a punishment.</item>
        <item>-The oldest drinkable beer in the world was found in 2010, in an early 19th-century shipwreck discovered near Finland. The beer was preserved in bottles by the cold abyss and it tasted very old (unsurprisingly), with some burnt notes and an acidic aftertaste.</item>
        <item>-The first professional brewers were all women called brewsters. The women had to be very beautiful to be able to become brewsters.</item>
        <item>-The world\rs largest beer festival is Oktoberfest. Held annually in Munich, Germany, it is a 16-day funfair running from late September to the first weekend in October with more than 6 million people from around the world attending the event every year.</item>
        <item>-At any given time, 0.7% of the world population is drunk. It means 50 million people are drunk right now. Beer is obviously the main contributor to the drunkenness.</item>
        <item>-The foamy head is a very important part of the beer. It is formed by a complex carbon-dioxide reaction and can say a lot about the quality of the beer. If the head is missing, it can mean that your beer is flat and bland-tasting.</item>
        <item>-Beer and marijuana have more in common than you would think. Beer\rs hops are in the same family of flowering plants as marijuana.</item>
        <item>-Beer strengthens bones. It is rich in silicon that increases calcium deposits and minerals for bone tissue.</item>
        <item>-George Washington had his own brewhouse on the grounds of Mount Vernon.</item>
        <item>-It was the accepted practice in Babylon, 4,000 years ago, that for a month after the wedding, the bride’s father would supply his son-in law with all the mead he could drink.</item>
        <item>-There are 19 different versions of Guinness</item>
        <item>-According to a diary entry from a passenger on the Mayflower, the pilgrims made their landing at Plymouth Rock, rather than continue to their destination in Virginia, due to lack of beer.</item>
        <item>-A barrel contains 31 gallons of beer. What Americans commonly refer to as a keg is actually 15.5 gallons, or a half-barrel.</item>
        <item>-Before thermometers were invented, brewers would dip a thumb or finger into the mix to find the right temperature for adding yeast. Too cold, and the yeast wouldn’t grow. Too hot, and the yeast would die. This thumb in the beer is where the phrase “rule of thumb” comes from.</item>
        <item>-In 1788, Ale was proclaimed “the proper drink for Americans” at a parade in New York City.</item>
        <item>-In English pubs, ale is ordered by pints and quarts. So in old England, when customers got unruly, the bartender would yell at them to mind their own pints and quarts and settle down. It’s where we get the phrase “mind your P’s and Q’s.”</item>
        <item>-The original text of the Reinheitsgebot (Germany’s Beer Purity Law) only had three ingredients: barley, hops and water. Yeast wasn’t mentioned for another 35 years.</item>
        <item>-12-ounces of a typical American pale lager actually has fewer calories than 2 percent milk or apple juice.</item>
        <item>-In 1963, Jim Whitaker became the first American to reach the summit of Mt. Everest. A can of Seattle’s own Rainier Beer made the ascent with him.</item>
        <item>-In 2010, the world’s oldest drinkable beer was found on a Baltic Sea shipwreck. The ship is believed to have sailed over 200 years ago.</item>
        <item>-Yeast can only survive alcohol concentrations of 14% to 18%.</item>
        <item>-In ancient Egypt, workers living in Giza often received rations of beer three times a day as payment.</item>
        <item>-The United States is the second largest hop producer in the world (behind Germany).</item>
        <item>-In 2003, Hermanus’s Birkenhead Brewery had a delivery truck that had a very unusual slogan painted on it: “Birkenhead Beer - helping ugly people have sex since 1852\r\r. The people of Hermanus went ballistic. There were threats of violence, stoning, boycotts and banning. The funny thing is people still, after 11 years, remember the truck, and the Birkenhead staff are often asked if they still have that truck. </item>
        <item>-Hops are poisonous to pets so keep a sharp eye on your pellets if you’re homebrewing.</item>
        <item>-According to legend, barrel-aged beers were created by accident when a whisky distillery tried to create a whisky finished with ale flavours.</item>
        <item>-Ancient Egyptian texts have been found that contain over 100 medicinal uses for beer.</item>
        <item>-In medieval Europe, the average person drank 220 to 250 litres of beer a year! As it had undergone fermentation, it was cleaner and safer to drink than the water.</item>
        <item>-In the 1600s, midwives created super-strong beer to ease the pain of labor!</item>
        <item>-In the middle ages, children were encouraged to drink beer for nutritional benefits.</item>
        <item>-Storing bottled beer upright minimizes oxidation and contamination from the cap.</item>
        <item>-“Hangover” in Norwegian is directly translated to “carpenters in the head”.</item>
        <item>-Isohumulones are a type of alpha acid in hops that aid in head retention.</item>
        <item>-Hops have loads of health benefits and are supposed to help with joint inflammation, insomnia, respiratory spasms and indigestion. So drink up for your health!</item>
        <item>-Brewers are known for being passionate and surprisingly superstitious. I know of a brewer overseas who dropped a screwdriver into his first brew by mistake. Now he drops it in every time.</item>
        <item>-Adding some beer to your marinade is supposed to soften the meat. The acids in the beer go to work on the proteins in the meat, whether it’s cooked or uncooked.</item>
        <item>-You can use beer to shine up any old copper items.</item>
        <item>-You can use beer as a conditioner. Apparently good quality brews will leave your hair silky and soft.</item>
        <item>-The sugar in beer is said to supercharge your plants. Beer sprinkler, anyone?</item>
        <item>-Yeast in beer converts into two things: ethanol (which attributes to the drunk feeling) and CO2 (which makes the bubbles).</item>
        <item>-Beer is stored in darker bottles as exposure to light will spoil the brew. Green bottles are associated with premium beers, while in fact, these beers are prone to get "light struck". Brown bottles are better for beer.</item>
        <item>-The Code of Hammurabi decreed that bartenders who watered down beer would be executed.</item>
        <item>-A cloud near the constellation Aquila contains enough ethyl alcohol to fill 400 trillion trillion pints of beer.</item>
        <item>-Coined in the early 1900s, the word "alcoholiday" means leisure time spent drinking.</item>
        <item>-During WWII, a bear named Wojtek joined the Polish army. He transported ammunition and sometimes drank beer.</item>
        <item>-Fried beer won Most Creative Fried Food at the 2010 Texas State Fair.</item>
        <item>-The top five states for beer consumption per capita: 1. North Dakota, 2. New Hampshire, 3. Montana, 4. South Dakota 5. Wisconsin.</item>
        <item>-Germany is home to a beer pipeline. Taps in Veltsin-Arena are connected by a 5km tube of beer.</item>
        <item>-Thomas Jefferson wrote parts of the Declaration of Independence in a Philadelphia tavern.</item>
        <item>-At the end of Prohibition, FDR said, "What America needs now is a drink."</item>
        <item>-Winston Churchill called the concept of Prohibition "an affront to the whole history of mankind."</item>
        <item>-George Washington insisted his continental army be permitted a quart of beer as part of their daily rations.</item>
        <item>-Oktoberfest originally started as a festival celebrating the 1810 marriage of Crown Prince Ludwig.</item>
        <item>-At spas in Europe, you can literally bathe in beer as a physical and mental therapeutic treatment.</item>
        <item>-In the 1990s, the Beer Lovers Party ran candidates in Belarus and Russia.</item>
        <item>-J.K. Rowling invented Quidditch in a pub.</item>
        <item>-Beer helped Joseph Priestly discover oxygen. He noticed gases rising from the big vats of beer at a brewery and asked to do some experiments.</item>
        <item>There is a crater on the moon named Beer.</item>
        <item>-Beer soup was a common breakfast in medieval Europe.</item>
        <item>An open-air beer fountain dispenses free beer to the public at the start of Bavarian Beer Week in Germany, </item>
        <item>-In the 1980s, a beer-drinking goat was elected mayor of Lajitas, TX.</item>
        <item>-Egypt was likely the first civilization to tax beer. Queen Cleopatra imposed a tax on beer in order, she claimed, to discourage public drunkenness, though it is widely believed that the tax was actually used to raise money to fund war with Rome.</item>
        <item>-Beer is the most popular alcoholic beverage in the United States. According to a 2016 Gallup poll, 43% of Americans who drink alcohol say they prefer beer (32% say wine and 20% say liquor). In 2015, the federal government collected $3.6 billion in excise taxes on domestic and imported beer alone.</item>
        <item>-In 1695, Great Britain raised taxes on beer, making gin the cheapest beverage in England. Gin was taxed at 2d (about 2 pennies) per gallon, while beer was taxed at 4 shillings 9d (about 57 pennies) per gallon. The difference in price is considered the root of a serious drinking problem in the country in the 18th century, especially among the poor.</item>
        <item>-In the United States, taxes on the production, distribution, and sale eat up 40% of the retail price of beer. That amount includes all taxes imposed on beer: the federal excise tax is about 5 cents per drink (the nickel comes from the assumption that the average beer has an alcohol content of 4.5%). The actual tax rate is $18 per barrel of beer, or 10 cents per ounce of alcohol .</item>
        <item>-German beers are often labeled "Gebraut nach dem Bayerischen Reinheitsgebot von 1516" which translates roughly to "brewed according to the Bavarian Purity Law of 1516." The law originally limited the ingredients which can be used to make beer in Germany (barley malt, hops, yeast, and water) and allowed the government to tax beer. The Reinheitsgebot became an official part of the German tax code in 1919 but was largely gutted when Germany became part of the European Union.</item>
        <item>-Arthur Guinness II - the father of Guinness stout - altered the family beer recipe to include unmalted roasted barley instead of black malt. The unmalted barley wasn\rt subject to extra taxes which made it affordable for the Guinness family - it also made the beer\rs taste distinctive. By the end of the 19th century, Guinness was the largest brewery in Europe.</item>
        <item>-According to the Beer Institute, directly and indirectly, the beer industry employs more than 1.75 million Americans (found in more than 4,000 breweries and importers and 6,690 distributors), providing nearly $79 billion in wages and benefits. The industry pays nearly $49 billion in business, personal and consumption taxes.</item>
        <item>-In 1991, President George H.W. Bush signed a bill which raised taxes on luxuries such as furs, yachts, private jets, jewelry and expensive cars (despite the "no new taxes" pledge) - that same bill nearly doubled the tax on beer. Bush called for the repeal of the tax just two years later, and while most of the taxes included in the bill were eventually repealed, the tax on beer remained in place and is still there today.</item>
        <item>-The most expensive state to buy a beer may be Tennessee where state excise taxes reach a whopping $1.29 per gallon, the highest in the country. The cheapest state to buy a beer? Wyoming, where the excise tax is just $.02 per gallon.</item>
        <item>-The most popular state to grab is a beer is Nevada  where beer is taxed at $0.16/gallon in addition to sales tax. The least popular state? Utah which has some of the highest taxes on alcohol in the country.</item>
        <item>-The oldest operating brewing company in the U.S. is D.G. Yuengling and Son, owned by Forbes billionaire Richard Yuengling, Jr. Yuengling ("Ying-ling" and not "Yoong-ling" or "Yang-ling"), based in Pottsville, Pennsylvania, is one of the country\rs five largest beer companies with an estimated $550 million in annual revenue in 2015. The company added a new location in Florida and won\rt promise to remain in Pennsylvania, blaming the state\rs tax climate in 2012: "Pennsylvania is a great location. But it’s not very business-friendly. You look for fair tax breaks, fair taxation. And the bottom line is more jobs. That’s what it’s all about."</item>
        <item>-According to Infogroup, with 1.54 beer-related businesses per capita, Bend, Oregon is the most favorable U.S. city for beer lovers. Oregon boasts two cities on the list: it probably helps that Oregon has no state sales tax to boost prices.</item>
        <item>-Recent data from the Brewers Association shows that craft beer accounts for 22% of the U.S. beer market with $25.5 billion in sales. Craft breweries are small: that can be a plus on the tax side since breweries which produce fewer  than 2 million barrels annually pay a reduced federal excise tax rate.</item>
        <item>-The oldest known recipe is for a 4,000-year-old beer made by the Sumerians. </item>
        <item>-Ethanol, the intoxicant in beer, is a powerful antiseptic, but not a good cold remedy. The optimal blood alcohol content to kill germs would be more than 60 percent.</item>
        <item>-Researchers at the University of Western Ontario found that micronutrients called polyphenols in one 12-ounce (0.35-liter) bottle of beer create protective levels of plasma antioxidants that can prevent heart disease. But at three bottles a day, the cardiovascular benefits of beer are reversed by the pro-oxidants your body creates as it metabolizes excess ethanol. </item>
        <item>-You might have known that fact if you were a beer expert, or cerevisaphile — a word derived from the Latin name of the Roman goddess of agriculture, Ceres, and vis, meaning strength.</item>
        <item>-“Aplenty bahl steinber horn!” means “A really great beer!” in Boontling, a folk language developed by workers in the hop fields of California’s Anderson Valley.</item>
        <item>-Hops, the bittering agent in beer, belong to the family Cannabaceae, making them marijuana’s close cousins and lending a little perspective to the term “hopped up.” </item>
        <item>-Try an experiment: Tilt the glass to see if foam adheres to the side. If it does, that’s called “Brussels lace,” considered by some to be a sign of high-quality beer — and clean glasses.</item>
        <item>-According to a study from the London Business School, political differences dictate American beverage choice: Conservatives prefer domestic pours such as Busch to imports like Guinness.</item>
        <item>-Guinness, to pour a perfect pint of the company’s stout, you need to let it rest for exactly 119.5 seconds between the first pour and the top-up — a period called the surge and settle.</item>
        <item>-Zymurgy is the study and practice of yeast fermentation in brewing.</item>
    </string-array>

</resources>